hey Josh what's up man hey dude not much
why don't you have any of your stupid
lights on ever since sergy I just I
can't get around the room to plug them
in and stuff what surgery uh the hip
surgery I had last week have you not
been watching our Channel I literally
post about it every day I don't watch
this [__] are you
kidding you don't you don't watch our
own show no I watch Joe Rogan and good
shows you're going to want to watch
today's episode though let me tell you
what okay today's episode we got a great
guest his name is Joe Fels great dude
yeah he did go to jail for a little bit
but awesome guy and I think people are
really going to enjoy his second
[Music]
story welcome to Second Story everybody
I'm Josh zabski with me as always is
Cory Lecky Corey what's going on nothing
man what's going on with you
just living buddy just living today we
got a special guest with us and I just
realized that I forgot the pronunciation
of your last name so I might completely
mess it up but that's okay we got with
us today uh influencer real estate
extraordinaire I don't know what else to
call you Joe Fels Joe what's going on
man uh drinking a beer in my
van how do I do it how did I do on your
last name did I get was I close dude you
know what you nailed it and the craziest
thing about it it's the Z [__] him up
if it was FS everybody knock it out of
the park fails yeah you got it there do
it actually he's German German well
seemed like Fells to me I don't know I
don't know where the confusion was
wellow I'm
dyslexic that's where the confusion was
for me so you thought it was Ness yeah
no maybe I don't know anyways so Joe is
uh
probably I would have to put you down as
one of the most most interesting people
that I've ever come across your story
just really everything about what it is
that you're doing so very excited to
talk to you and we're very excited to
have you here today so we are Second
Story of course we like to talk to
people who have g undergone a major
change in their life that sent them down
a different path you've had a few you've
talked about well you've talked to me
about them we're going to try to narrow
it down to maybe one or two today so
we're going to start with your second
story so the is yours Joe well I like
you said I've had a few second stories
but I think the most marketed and
contrasting one would be you know going
from fresh out of prison to self-made
millionaire in a span of about 10 years
I
mean I got out of prison on uh 8 n
10 uh and I was penniless I had $50 the
clothes on my back and the love of my
family uh I paroled out to the house I
grew up in in Augusta Sandy Run Court
it's where Sandy run original comes from
uh that was on 8910 and then again on
8922 I packed everything in a van
disillusioned with Modern Life and left
for the West Coast a self-made
millionaire and a bit of a Real Estate
Mogul right here in
Augusta so just to give people an idea
of how you've done in real estate at
this point in time how many properties
how many real estate properties do you
have if you don't mind
saying I really don't keep up with it
but it's 65 is I don't know I mean I
really don't it how much money's in your
bank account if you know I have no
[__] clue
enough so but but really 60 65 is most
of them are in uh
Georgia uh I do have vacation airbnbs in
Tennessee and Washington State I did
have one in Carolina but I sold it
because me and the HOA didn't quite see
I ey um but uh man I have them most of
them are rental properties some of them
are vacant lots that I've bought to
speculate on but the vast majority are
cash flowing rental properties and I uh
only have four mortgages right now um
all have come in the last four years I
bought 50 houses without a single
mortgage um over 50 houses I probably
bought and sold
myself just myself around 100 to 150
houses without the use of a single
mortgage yeah that's Bonkers so
something that always comes across by
Social Media stuff is uh tends to be
real estate Moguls and a lot of it at
least from my perspective a lot of it is
like guys in suits kind of sleazy they
sort of remind you of like the the
lawyer type yeah there you go
um for our audio listeners let's just
say Joe's making a sign we'll just we'll
call it sign kind some kind of hand
gesture some kind of hand gesture yeah
some kind of hand sure that's a that's a
really nice way to put it for our audio
listeners uh for the creeps they they
obviously can see what's going on um
they know what I'm doing yeah yeah yeah
yeah the creeps I'm sure they're aware
yeah I'm sure they're aware uh so it
it's I I find it kind of interesting
because I I found you through the
algorithm because I am somebody who's
interested in real estate I do get like
the Grant Cardone types uh the Chris
Crone types real estate Moguls who dress
nice fancy cars the whole deal and then
there was you that came in and you are
not those things and that immediately
piqued my interest because you're kind
of everything that they're not and I
think that's awesome so a lot of people
want to know nowadays how do how does
somebody make money in real estate how
do they make a fortune and what sort of
story did they have to get there so for
you let's start at the beginning let's
go all the way back we're going to start
with your childhood
so I I know your Origins but let's uh
let's get into it so where were you born
what was your childhood like well well
I'll tell you where do you did you tell
Corey where I was born because if not I
want you to guess Corey where I told you
Cory did you I don't listen yet so dude
this this [__] is not good for the old
memory but it's great for everything
else okay I'm not gonna guess you tell
me in a van were you born in a van I
wasn't that cool pretty
close I wish I had I might have been
conceived in one you never know but well
I
uh I was born in Papa New Guinea um my
parents were uh missionaries to tribes
over there in in ukarumpa that were
eating each other two generations prior
these were longtime head hunters and
cannibals man and they lived in Huts I
was born in a little like single wide
Rundown trailer that was dropped off
there and to put it in perspective when
I was born they took the placenta
outside and threw it in a hole my dad
delivered me I almost died in childbirth
uh complications my dad had to pull me
out with the forceps an unapproved
medical technique and ukara Papa New
Guinea uh and my entire life has been a
fight ever since my dad was a medical
doctor man believe it or not he
uh he was never really concerned with
money he wasn't get paid [__] over there
and he took a residency in Rockford
Illinois where they liveed for a while
and then
uh they eventually came down to MCG
that's how we got to Augusta um and I'm
I'm a Richmond County boy um you know
I'm a real Rough and Tumble guy but I'm
the only one like this in my family like
I come from a pretty like well I'm not
gonna say normal everybody in my family
is an absolute stud
I did not know that until I left and
have been all around the world but
everybody in my family is a stud my dad
was a sub three-hour marathon runner my
mother has a black belt in American
kickboxing and has the ESPN app
installed with notifications she road
trip to the National Championship Game
on three days notice and watch Bama beat
uh Bama lose to Georgia the first time
like we're all nuts she's 72 and she's
still going like that um W your brother
too your brother was a is a lawyer
right my brother is partner at Alon and
bird I hope he doesn't mind me saying
that um but he is partner in Alon bird
that was a company that defended Apple
in the San Bernardino iPhone shooting he
does intellectual property Law data
privacy stuff he's a very secretive
individual I don't know what all he does
but he's up to something
so shout out to your brother my brother
Tim is an absolute stud my brother Tim
let me give him a shout out he wrote a
book and was the first van lifer he
spent nine months in a Volkswagen bus he
built himself touring the US getting uh
vendors for his online startup un
Grocery and wrote a book about it dude
and read the book I'm telling you it's
called top dead center you gotta read it
it's phenomenal um that's awesome that
sounds good my Uncle Paul's a national
champion kickboxer was in the Guinness
Book of World Records for skateboarding
uh he's also a pretty renowned Mosaic
artist look him up new school mosaics
Paul Perman uh Axel Rose has seven of
his belt buckles Rolling Stone like he's
yeah so wow I come from a kind of
interesting family uh yeah
but I doe people don't never like people
don't get it I grew up there we didn't
have a TV we went to church and we were
Outdoors like we were we were raised
like we was in the 50s dude looking back
on it my whole life I've really just
wanted to be [__] cool like I never
really gave [__] about school I don't it
just seemed like a bunch of [__] to
me it always has it's always been a
[__] game to me like in
retrospect I've seen through their
[__] [__] my whole life and I've
never I've never cared your dad
obviously was pretty educated how did he
feel about something like that you kind
of uh questioning like through your
childhood just kind of questioning
school and stuff like that was your dad
no opin no so no oh no my parents were
on me dude I mean I had great I great
great parents hated them growing up oh
boy uh I mean very strict very strict at
one point in my life later on we'll get
there later I was kicked out of my
parents house for rolling a joint of
catnip
catnip catnip what are we gonna do with
it what were we gonna do with it that's
what yeah yeah you sh yeah okay Mom I
was gon to smoke that [__] I mean what
what do you mean that's what I'm saying
like but but is that what's in that
joint right there no this is West Coast
oregano oregano that one West Coast
oregano uh you know what they say man a
quarter a day keeps his do her away
yeah there you go so I I got a quick
question around like your childhood like
I you've been quoted to say that you've
always had an entrepreneurial Spirit
you've always had that entrepreneurial
Drive um how far back does that go in
your mind look here homeboy I was
selling candy to kids in middle
school okay and I actually well well see
when I say
entrepreneurial I'm a different type of
entrepreneur because I don't give a [__]
about
money okay I could not tell you until
now because I looked him up I couldn't
tell you how much I've made a single
year of my life
and I've never said this before in a
public form until
now other than a a a small period where
I had to for tax purposes where I drew
$249 uh a week I have never drawn a
salary of any kind out of any company
that I
own and I am live like a
popper that's how I am um nice I live in
a van I'm standing in it right
now I I bought this off of a guy working
on his moped on Highway 56 the video is
on Instagram look it
up I found these in a camper last week
um and what I'm saying the jeans are the
boots the jeans are the boots no you
didn't see these dude these are these
are hold on can I I gotta pan down dude
yeah yeah go for these are these are um
vintage
joggers oh nice with the Jack they're
wind they're wind Breakers dude these
things are more 90s than Will Smith dog
um I'm telling yeah good stuff if it's
not about money like what's it about
then can uh can you say about for me one
more time sir oh Jesus just one just one
more I'll answer it
but if it's not about money what's it
about a
boot oh boy it's not about how how do
you say it about if it's not about
you know it's so funny Alex and I have
this conversation all the time because
she says I say things funny like wind
pain and she be like what' you say i' be
like wind pain about uh about that's not
a word we they all [__] up it's got to
end in an R if it ends in an R not dog
half of it getting cut
off all right but but what is it about
I'll be honest with you man well a few
things about me one I am highly
competitive okay highly competitive
um and this is a game everybody on Earth
is playing
everybody whether you know it or not
yeah we're all playing and you know like
I mean that's the that's the thing and
in America as a man whether you know it
or not you are conditioned get money
[__] [__] that's what you're like fed
in your brain no matter what your
parents teach you that's what you were
fed by American Media get money [__]
[__] rise to the top that's it um and
so like that's where we are like we're
competitive and men are naturally
competitive and yeah I am I'm a little
guy but I'm competitive and I'm good at
winning like I want a lot of [__] in my
life um and so yeah I like to compete
and
two the more money I have the less money
[__] bags can have like oil companies
this is a giant tool and if I get a
whole lot of it I can control control it
and if I control a lot of property
[__] if you don't like your
neighbors just pick them that's been a
Joe Fels quote for a long time where I'm
parked right now I own 22 houses in that
neighborhood I got a neighborhood watch
built in um it's it's called having a
village and then you know lastly I think
God lets me get blessed with money
because he knows I'm not driven by the
love of money and if I ever get some
I'll do something great with it like I
don't know Buy
a thousand acres of rainforest and
employ the indigenous tribes to shoot
anybody on site that goes out there you
know like something crazy with it that
that San or more normal Minds would
never do yeah so I mean then I'm serious
about that I uh I like just being free
man money's a it's smoking mirrors guys
that's what it is money is just [__]
smoking mirrors you have never comprenda
this in your life but all it takes is
two people to have a Day and hit a wrong
button if these are the presidents of
two countries and all the power goes out
you ain't got no more [__]
money you understand yeah and the only
reason that money has value is because
we all agree it has money it doesn't
even exist it's it's literally your
imagination but we're so deep in it that
you can't you don't even know you're in
it bro that's how deep it goes and like
I just I don't know why I just if you
can tell I can tell by look on your face
I you know I don't exist there and I
never have yeah yeah it's Faith right
that's what money is that's kind of what
I expect you to say I expected you to
say it's it's about gaining that freedom
so I [__] hate money dude I really do
if you think about it money has caused
more
[__] than anything else and it is
the main leading destruction or the main
money is the main leading cause of the
destruction of planet Earth that's it
pretty much saying people are trying
what they're cutting down the rainforest
to grow more cows to do what to sell
beef to make fat people fatter like what
the [__] I just can't yeah so I'll get
animated out that because it pisses me
off to no [__] end it's very rarely
enough for people and that's the problem
right um I wanted to talk about your
competitiveness so just to jump back to
your child no no no it's all good it's
good stuff to jump back to your
childhood because you and I talked about
this when we spoke on the phone yeah you
were you're obviously very competitive
but you were as a child very prolific
athlete right still
sir well I see you run yeah you're still
you're still an athlete but back in the
day you you had scholarships right to go
to to go to school so I I had a chance
to I did I I never had an academic I
mean athletic scholarship I had two
academic scholarships that I went to
University of Georg on when I was in
high school I was a standout wrestler um
I also no lie was our starting nose
guard at
5'4 140ish pounds um and I was a starter
on the varsity of the football team too
and I was a scrapper dog everybody knew
it
um I had a chance to wrestle uh in
college coach Le got me an audition and
the discussion was if you get this
you'll get a quarter ride and they'll
pay for your
books and it was a at UNCC chap Hill cuz
that's where he wrestled he knew
somebody and I think I didn't lose a
match that year until State I injured my
shoulder hip tossing the kid tore my
trap out a little bit standard [__] but
I I was a good wrestler and I remember
he was talking to me on Friday he said
hey Tri outs or tomorrow here's where
you go and you need to be there this
early for your drug tests and everything
and I was like what do you
mean what you mean hey what you what you
talk about Coach L they think I take
sterile
sh I wrestle 119 PB no oh you can't
smoke oh I ain't even go
nope how prepost y'all [__]
want me to weigh 125 pounds during
college and I can't even smoke no weed
[__]
[Laughter]
that and I was uh promptly kicked out of
the University of Georgia my second
semester for cannabis hash and mushrooms
okay
lost yeah man I was that was my first
Mel
charges oh was a f okay that's where
happened so all right so that kind of
gets into your story a little bit so you
mentioned first felony charges first
felony charge how old were you at that
point so I think I was
17 so I graduated in 04 in ' 05 no class
04 and I
turned so 04 [__] math is hard 86 you
know I was so I graduated when I 17 yeah
I was 18 so I was 18 when that happened
man um and uh I remember
dude it's so [__] up man I stand out
have you ever noticed
that no not you okay and I've been like
this my whole life when I was in
elementary school
we had Show and Tell back then you know
what I brought for show and
tell a 22b snapping turtle that we
caught in the creek and back then they
let we demonstrated I brought snakes
dude I was I was well known they called
me Oki phoi Joe I mean I always stood
out when I was 11 I caught two
copperheads bare-handed by myself at a
church picnic um it was published in a
family it was published in a magazine
back then focus on the family my dad did
it was a church thing um
we need to find that but uh is you
holding two snakes no yeah I caught two
copperheads bare-handed and wasn't bit
yeah that's kind of yeah yeah that's
wild ironic yeah but uh man um yeah dude
when I went to ug I I stood out I was in
the top Farm I stayed in 929
Creswell um and I dude I tell you it was
amazing I grew up without a TV in austa
Georgia and a shelter Conservative
Christian home and I was now at the
University of
Georgia I had arrived like dude it was
like a three to one girl to guy ratio in
the freshman class and like a uhuh three
to2 hot girl to guy ratio dude the the
goods were odd and the odds were good
like I mean
yeah man and like R Springer dude it was
literally the sense of like I'm kind of
tripping back back a little bit thinking
about it man I haven't thought about
this stuff in
years like I really haven't I haven't
thought about this part of it in years
guys and so like it was a sense of
Freedom like I'd never known
exhilarating um you know I've been
grinding my whole [__] life uh
when I was
15 the running I used to wake up at
night at 1212 in the morning just
bursting with energy and I just go run
around the neighborhood literally and
one night my dad had a premonition like
hey you know let me go check on my son
he woke up and I have kids now we've all
done it uh I do it and he came down and
I was
gone now we're talking this is in 2002
you know I know what now I know why he
was freaking the [__] out you go down
there have with a bad gut feeling your
kid's gone you know there's no cell
phones or nothing no word no and then I
come back I was just on a run what's
wrong dad and we just freaking out they
started taking me to psychiatrist around
that time um
at least you didn't come back with
snakes on that one you know and man so
like I've been you know [__] training
and wrestling and working you know I
graduated number nine in my class you
know I went to ug on two academic
scholarships I was not a very driven
student but I was always training or
doing something I went to the governor's
honors program when I was a junior
that's one of the most prestigious
things you can do academically in high
school uh they send you to valdosa state
to college for a summer look it up uh
and you'll see what I'm talking about I
mean it was a pretty big deal um
and so I really never even thought about
all that [__] it just kind of hit my
shoulder and rolled off it really like
in retrospect my whole life I never
really felt like I was doing anything I
don't know maybe because I was the black
sheep of my family I definitely was and
still am um and you know if I just had a
clean slate I knew I only knew a few
people you know it was a clean slate I
could be whoever I wanted to be and I
have always just wanted to be [__]
cool it's hard when you're the church
family yeah but but at Westside High
School the Fels Brothers me and Tim I
mean we were like yeah they they knew us
I mean we were popular in high school I
got two senior superlatives and rule is
you can only get one but I was given two
awards for most top and Class
Clown
really there was no I mean the results
were unanimous I it was no second place
it was
100 um you got your felony charge when
you were 18 your first one did that lead
to any prison time or what happened with
that no I played first offender on that
um and I I I wound
up getting probation uh first Defender 5
years probation if I would have
completed it you know clean slate you
know type deal um I had a good attorney
and I mean it
was it was weed and hash and mushrooms
like who gives a [__] these are called
plants dog yeah nowadays it' be
absolutely well maybe not so much in
some states but yeah it it wouldn't be
such a big deal well I'd like to point
something out though they're
wrong I mean they're just all wrong like
during hey during during the Salem which
trials they thought they were right and
during slavery they thought they were
right and during the Spanish Inquisition
they thought they were right but they
were just [__] wrong and all it took
was a little bit of time and look hey
they're [__] wrong I'm telling you
just wait for a few more old white guys
to die duh uh so what was your second
charge so just to give people an idea
there's more than one so we'll get into
I don't know if we'll get into each one
but we'll kind of go down down the
timeline a little bit so that one I
think the next
one and I'm going to go out go ahead and
say for the things I've been charged
with criminally except for one possible
exception I have never committed a
goddamn
crime not in my mind I'm just here to
tell you like I really haven't I've
never done anything to anyone what I
have done has
literally what I did would literally be
considered minding your own [__]
business in most parts of the world like
yeah the next time I got in trouble was
the only time that I ever really did
anything bad and I feel I felt terrible
about this I have made amends for it I
went out to the church and I I stroke
him a check I look the pastor in the eye
she didn't even know who I was it was a
different Pastor I've made this more
than right but I have felt so bad about
it because it's literally like in my
mind the only sin I've ever committed to
this level like I shouldn't have done
this man like I I I I did wrong to a
place that was so good to me it was a
church Campground out there in Lincoln
County that I grew up going to and it
was close the core Engineers the [__]
government didn't renew their lease and
so you you know they were going to tear
down the A-frames and everything and so
we just went out there and we're
partying and we got really hammered and
we went and we shot a a fire
extinguisher off in one of the
A-frames is old raggedy A-frame
condemned to be tore down but like we
vandalized this place we kicked in a
door um nothing nothing terrible but
that was it and there was a family
reunion coming out there the next day
just so happened they got there cars are
all there they called the cops I get
arrested but uh that was just
misdemeanor dude and those cops were
good man like I'll be honest they were
good they let us load up in the car and
the girl one of the girls named Ashley
they let her drive and follow them to
jail so we didn't have to pay to get the
car
towed I mean like in pretty nice cop
yeah and he I remember he looked at he
says guys I'm doing this cuz I got a
daughter
and I'd want him to give him this option
do not
run and and we were all like you know
I've run from the cops five times on
foot and only been caught twice [__]
them um
like man uh the next one
was probably the biggest croc of [__]
you'd ever see in your life but I was
smoking weed and drinking beer at a
place known as hippie Co
out there in South in uh out there at
Clark Hill Lake Thurman whatever the
[__] they call it now and
uh the DNR the federal uh enforcement
division was watching me with binoculars
from a
boat okay they pulled up on and but
literally it's just me and my
girlfriend literally yeah
it was like
it okay literally and we we had more
than an ounce of cannabis
why well like I mean duh like you get
pun like it's cheaper that way what do
you mean duh
[__] if they had have waited an hour it
would have been less than an ounce but
that's what I'm saying like literally
we're sitting there and they those
[__] ass clowns waited for me to go
down they literally this what did those
[__] ass clowns I went down and I
jumped in the water and I cooled off it
was in May or July it was in the
summertime it's hot down south now and I
went and I sat on a rock I was sitting
on a rock and I had a towel I took a
towel I wrapped it around me and I took
my shorts off and I rung them out and
I'm sitting them on this rock to dry and
I literally I'm sitting them like that
and these [__] pull up on me in
a
boat well and you know and they
literally got out and said where's the
dope what are you doing what do you mean
what am I doing I'm
[__] what I'm sitting in the sun on
the bank of the lake like what [__] you
man you know like I didn't tell him that
I was scared shitless like uh dude
that's the thing I'm an 18 dude you
think about I'm an 18y old kid drunk
drunk off my ass [__] swimming in the
lake like I'm literally minding my own
[__] business to the nth
degree and they are sitting out there
with binoculars watching me now look at
this there's a [__] guy enjoying life
and swimming in the lake and here's your
tax dollars at work watching you like
the [__]
Gusto yeah paying the Peeping Toms yeah
dude it's just it blows my mind it's the
most unjust [__] Croc of [__] I've
ever thought about dude and this is the
type of [__] that stole my innocence man
like I was a real tender hearted
Southern boy now and you can tell by
talking to me I'm a lot to [__] with
right now man I
mean yeah and and and like because dude
like if you take a dog when he's young
and you [__] kick him a lot he's
gonna be mean when he gets older I
promise and he's not GNA give a [__]
about your
feelings and man when when you've been
treat been treated like that by these
people [__] them and so well if you pull
up on me in a boat and tell me you're
going to take me to jail what do you
think I do I looked at this [__] sack
of [__] caught behind me and I said beat
your feet [__] doom and so I
took off and I ran I was coming up this
hill and my daddy always taught me pass
him on the Hills son that's a fail's
thing we run Hills we do not run on flat
ground we're not [__] um and I coming
on this hill and I like oh boy Smokey
ain't gonna give me him and goddamn I
kicked my sandals off and I scooped him
up like that and he said don't do it I
said [__] you and I took off I got in my
car and uh
when I hit the uh I got my car was so
drunk man I really I pulled right off
the thing and I went down I went I
pulled out of the parking lot and I went
out and I was like oh [__] dude you just
ran from the cops like oh [__] and I was
like I pulled off immediately and went
down and pulled off in the woods and
passed out and
uh they had a boat I did not know they
also had a helicopter that was a good
move it's a real good move
it's a veteran move right there so what
are we up to three is that three or four
ohow but uh man I had another uh I had
another I think like little minor of
possession another little misdemeanor
charge or something something stupid it
was dumb probation violation but then
the big one the last one happened
prophetically out there in Lincoln
County the same place we weren't at the
church Campground it was down here we
passed it and went on down the road to
the dead end we're dead end to the lake
and that's where it happened you know we
were in a pretty bad car accident and uh
they went to take me to jail I called my
mama man it's one of the most
heart-wrenching times in my life dude I
called my mom and I remember telling her
I said uh I was talking to her uh so
Rebecca
had you know she had quit breathing man
I'd given her mouth to mouth and
everything and I took her to this dude's
house and you some strangers house in
lincolon man and
uh you know it's [__] I don't know
what time it is I have no shirt on I'm
half
drunk um and I don't know I don't
[__] know she's not breathing I gave
her mouth to mouth she started she won't
breathing call the cops and dude was
[__] nuts they get there they're
taking her off in the thing
she and I I'm can I use your phone I
call my mom and I tell them what
happened I remember I'm like I had a
test in political science at Augusta
State the next day that's where my brain
was if that tells you anything that's
what I was so concerned about um and and
said they they said hey you got to come
take a breath while I said okay mama
mama I got to take a blow test I'll call
you back I love
you I didn't talk to her for almost two
years
um and
uh man I uh
I remember they they went I blew a
0.006 that's a 06 once again I didn't
[__] do anything and I'll never
forget man they said come with me and
and and I said okay and he took me over
to the car and then he kind of oh [__]
what he said and he grabbed my hands and
and I knew you know I knew what it
was and that dude guy I don't know if
you've ever had had that feeling
before man I was on probation I was
already on probation in two I was out on
[__] bond in South Carolina on
felony dope charges I'm already on
felony probation if that gets revoked
that's three [__] man n dog can't go
down like that not me you gonna you
gonna be catch me you gon have to beat
your feet fat boy boom as soon as you
went to grab for and [__] uh cuffs I
bucked and I'll never forget it was it
was starting to
sprinkle and I I I remember five cop
cars being there five cop cars an
ambulance and a goddamn [__] fire
truck
um uh and I'll never forget I went boom
and I took off and I slipped and I fell
I was barefooted no shirt barefooted um
and I they started laughing and I got up
and I fell again and I remember this
where you gonna go boy don't run and I
said [__] it gotta
go and I took
off
um I just for time's sake I'm not going
to tell you the whole story of that
night but I ran 20s something miles that
night and got a ride home in the most
insane way
imaginable okay
like the the the things and the the
sprinting across an open field in the
Moonlight because you think the dogs are
chasing you not seeing the barb wire
fence [__] like
that um and just it was pretty nuts and
uh I was
19 um and I ran away that night and I
had uh $7 and a mini big lighter in my
pocket and that was
it did you leave
town I was in
Kentucky three days
later w and you were on the run
for how long about so that was September
I want to say September and they caught
me two days so let's see that was
September of 07 I
believe um and they caught me two days
after my 21st birthday so it was about
it's around uh it's around 20 months man
um wow and I uh I was a fugitive
man what was
that like what was that feeling like
like that experience of just hey I'm
gonna tell you something guys I'm gonna
put this in perspective for you have you
ever run a
marathon yeah a short one
you five no a half
marathon here's probably I'd probably
run a 5k yeah like when I was younger so
you have in your had a conception of
what it feels like to run 26 miles
without stopping but you have no [__]
clue is what I'm trying going to tell
you just like everybody who ever stepped
in the ring with Conor McGregor thought
they knew what it would be like to be in
there with him until they woke up
unconscious like I cannot tell you I I
just I'm writing the book now and I just
call it the
dreads like I cannot describe have you
ever had anxiety anybody ever had a
panic attack you ever had one that's
[__]
real like that's what I'm that's what
I'm trying to tell you have you ever had
one that was real I'm literally running
for my [__] life and everything that
I know and love is gone and I'm
alone and I have
nothing and there's people looking for
me do you feel like that the whole time
or was that something you got over here
what I'm going to tell you man being a
fugitive is is you can get no rep
anytime you know the feeling of dude it
ha it would happen sometimes you know I
had some good times man I hit some licks
you know I worked hard that's that's
when I got in trade
work really um you know that's kind of
ironic that I'm an investor through
trade work um but uh I uh you know how
it feels on a a Friday afternoon on a
sunny fall day beautiful WEA you got
paid you got some money in the bank
[__] 50 Cent is playing on the
radio you know what I mean and uh you
just driving down the road it's like a
good day and you're feeling good I'd get
that sometimes and then all of a sudden
it hits
you you have no hope you don't
exist I mean that was it like you have
no hope you can't live like I'm a wanted
man I don't have a driver's license at
any point if need any essential service
I'm [__] I could go to the
hospital I was terrified to go get my my
pres I was out on bond bounty
hunters you know I mean like you know I
never had anyone look for me that I
noticed but I was on felony Bond it's
five grand on my head dog I mean that
was a lot of money in [__] I'd go find
your ass for five grand right now Cletus
[__] get in his van but uh it's
miserable man and just the just like I
said imagine a a panic attack that
that's real and contemplating yourself
this is a knowing that I feel terrible
and the feeling is valid and and and
proper and I dude I [__] I ran away I
jump my parents bonded me out of jail
and I ran away and wasn't turning myself
in they put their house up and I'm
dipping like you got to understand and
but I like told you I didn't [__] do
anything I just in some shival notion
why what
why why you're a [__] idiot Joe but
man that's one of my strengths and also
one of my weaknesses man is when I do
something I go all in and if I love
somebody I don't give a [__] like that's
how I am dude um I'm a very intense
person I probably didn't have to tell
you that but I mean it was the only
option at that time your woman's
getting you know you you can't you got
to take down on the chin big dog and
uh ah man just tough it's tough I cried
a lot uh those days it was dark days man
I got into pills I mean I did a lot of
drugs yeah I'm sure did you have a hard
time trusting trusting people during
that time like you'd almost think that
everybody could be somebody who's trying
to maybe take you down turn you in that
kind of thing yeah like while you're on
the Run yeah f F yeah man like I'm dude
going to the grocery
store I mean that's what I'm saying you
don't understand you wear a hat
everywhere and sunglasses and you're
just a
nobody you know that's what I'm saying
you're
you're you ain't going nowhere unless it
looks like the pleasure barge off of
[__] Star Wars you know what I mean
like like you're not going to places
that are above board man and you just
kind of blend into the part of society
that's a throwaway man I was throwaway I
was a fugitive man less than a few years
prior I was at ug on two full ride
scholarships with the bank account a car
I mean everything I was popular as an
athlete and I'm on the run from the
[__]
law crazy you want to talk about a stark
and all I was I was a Barefoot of
country boy I was out there at the lake
drinking having fun and like I said I
never did anything dumb or like except
one I wasn't out there acting a goddamn
fool I wasn't doing [__]
what so what was the point where you
were caught or turned yourself in so
after the 20
months man I uh I got caught I I run
from them again I'll never forget when I
took off that time when they went to
pull me over in that car um I I got
pulled over in a church parking lot and
they caught me in a church parking lot
here's a Joe ph's saying you could quote
this uh it's probably just a coincidence
just like everything else in my
[__] life uh just but I I was
got pulled over that church parking
lot and I slowed down and I put that bit
that old cutless I put it at uh neutral
and I left it rolling right at that
church and I jumped out that door and
gave him some [__] to worry about and I
took off
G and did you have a did you have an
alias like a different name at that time
that you were going by
Jay Jay yeah yeah I
mean people call me Jay I mean Jay
that's really
y did uh did you stay in Kentucky the
whole time or did you go to different
stat I came I came back to Georgia not
long after Kentucky's a commonwealth
state I don't know if it is now at the
time it was bounty hunters can't go
there so it made sense okay makes sense
did you have any close calls like in
that 20-month period where you almost
got caught I ran from the police two
more three times so I've run from I ran
from him three times in that
period uh and they caught me that last
time what was that like that where they
actually took you
down I hate losing
dog hey but like I said I I can beat
like I'm telling you uh and policemen
you know they're public servants um a
lot of them come from you know some of
the worst parts of society like they
really do man and uh they're all just
people like me when they go home and
take their costume off I mean and I drag
the [__] out of the vast majority of
them but when there's 14 of them and
they have [__] radios it's kind of
hard big dog um and I I zigged when I
should have zagged man they caught me in
a church parking lot um I'll never
forget sitting in the back of that that
Cruiser man I was sitting there like
this they were like what's your name
[__] you what's your name I just looked
at him what's your name shut the door
what's your name shut your name shut the
door please so you did have an alias no
yeah hey man take me to jail dog you
gonna find out who I am when we get just
take me to jail [__] ain't
nothing for us to talk about him did you
have any relief when you were caught
I've read I've you know read that from
people that sometimes like people who
commit murder or something have a relief
when they get caught eventually well I'm
going to tell you yes and no yes I did
feel relief um but you know the brain
has an amazing way of coming up with
coping strategies to keep you from
hanging yourself like I'm gonna tell you
let me find the pros in this prison cell
I mean yeah man like there was a sense
of relief kind of
like I don't know the sense of relief
you feel when you take one massive
diarrhea and you have a bunch more
behind it I mean
like oh boy that's
that was a great kidney stone can't wait
to get the rest of them out [__] I mean
yeah you know um so yeah I I did man I
I'll never forget that's what I did I I
went and I I remember I was reading a
house I mean a book called The House of
sand and fog by Andre de boy right there
uh you read that's what I was reading
the first the most memorable book I read
I was in I had so many chemicals in my
system I had to spend the the first 72
hours in the butt naked
cell [__] God guys that's tough and you
wonder how I'm such a [__] Savage now
that I'm talking about it well Goddamn
what the [__] do you expect you chase me
I was a I was a creature man and I
remember hey I come off of [__]
heroin and pills of all benzo dipin hard
withdrawals in a butt naked cell for 72
hours in a suicide smok it's a [__]
padded cell right all the way around
it's a padded cubicle like an 8 by10
there is nothing in this except a hole
in the floor with a grade in it for you
to [__] in they keep it 68 degrees and
all you are given is a suicide smok
which is specifically
designed for this one purpose if you're
going to kill yourself you're going to
do it wearing this buddy it's going to
drive you crazy you cannot in no way
shape or form get completely comfortable
there's always cold air hitting you at
all hours they give you a blanket at 10
p.m. and they take it away at
6 and they come and three times a day
the your your [__] food is put
through a [__] port at the door and
then they're giv that if you have to
[__] you just go [__] in the hole and
you have to go beat on the door until
they flush it and they never are in a
hurry welcome to so that was your uh
that was where you detoxed basically or
I guess started a
detox that's tough man
that's tough yeah that's yeah that's
that's pretty [__] up so after the
three days of that what happened to you
where did you go then I went to cmax
which is single cell you're in there by
yourself um I
uh it's just a
uh you know a regular dorm man uh I
think it was three tier two or three
tier cells and you're just there by
yourself and I was there for a month
just in a isolation then they put me in
gen Pop um in Columbia County now I will
say this if you have to pick a jail I
would highly recommend Columbia County
the butt naked Wing was not very nice
but the rest of it was by jails go
pretty [__] nice like I'll be honest
with you I gained like 40 pounds in nine
months I mean I was I was a porker when
I hit the Chang gang dog I'm telling you
um uh they I remember they had these
little drink fountains over on the side
with a little thing that shot it up and
it Trinkle down on the sides you can go
over there and fill up your little cups
and you could smoke sigs and the sheriff
over there uh I think it was Clay
Whittle I don't know I don't know he's
an [__] whoever he is but uh he had a
good theory um he he said I will never
tell them they can't smoke cigarettes as
long as I smoke cigarettes and he had a
point if [__] are in jail at
least let them smoke cigs they'll keep
them stabbing each other you [__]
[__] like
godamn um so it was pretty chill like we
ate really well dude um and it was
pretty cush there was there weren't any
fights like I mean it was laidback it
was like a day camp where I was um and
uh then they [__] me out man I I got a a
to5 um 15 years 10 uh five in and 10 on
probation and uh
they coming to [__] me out dog they
don't tell you when you're sentenced man
I never forget being sentenced
oh text Alex get me another beer
please
needed need it for this
one tough well while you wait for that
beer did you have and we haven't really
talked about any type of a trial you
you're obviously talking about
sentencing what was your trial like did
you have a
trial man let me just go on and tell
you um I
uh I
uh I remember talking to my public
defender the first
time and
uh that's a big thing in jail oh you're
your lawyer is coming oh [__] it's all
like it's the equivalent of a conjugal
visit dog um you know they give your
public defender showed up damn it's like
Daddy coming home in jail
anyways I [__] went to see him and he
uh I remember he sat down his name was
David Brooker brunker blonde guy really
a pretty good guy but bless his hard he
looked at the file and he said all right
sir um I see here you're on probation
for three felonies here you're on bond
for a drug felony here and here you were
pulled over you got out with the bag you
ran with the bag you got caught with the
bag it was full of
drugs how may I help you that's what he
did like and I was
like uh can you give me a plea bargain
he was like that's what I was thinking
like like yeah man yeah makes
sense I was looking at 55 years with all
you know you know that was The Backs
they could sentence me
to 55 years that's nuts my uncle
actually got me two years knocked off of
my sentence
man I I can't I can't tell you that one
he did but my Uncle Paul I just want to
credit him there he got two years
knocked off my sentence I'll be forever
grateful um you know he's an [__] we
butt heads a lot but uh he did man he
showed up when it mattered I'll give him
that
so so just for our audience how much
time did you actually spend in jail so
you got sentenced obviously maybe we
could Circle back to your sentencing
after you get a drink but how long did
you actually get uh sentenced for how
much time did you do in jail I did uh 30
months in total I did nine months in
jail and then 20 months in the Chang
gang Chang gang prison sorry that's a a
southern terminology and the more these
I drink the more Southern I
sound all
right when you're talking about when
you're talking about prison sounding
Southern kind of helps you know
yeah so so 30 months
total in prison you got your beer coming
here comes your beer you okay yeah hey
how much weeds in those lemon things
what the bars
yeah you want us to cut this
part hey nice to meet you what' you say
nice to meet you it said how much weed's
in the lemon thing
look at me enough I don't know that that
was a trial match literally he doesn't
know okay literally there's a lot and
and that that you can't you can't taste
it either can you no it's delicious I
know but that you can't taste the weed
that's the whole thing it's he doesn't
know how strong they are that's why he
gave are they
strong DJ stilt pise home
run meet you meet have fun enjoy that
night yeah that's gonna be a fun one
okay thank you B hey Anthony Portis you
just got a shout out dog you're gonna
love that that's going in your [__]
portfolio oh my God that's
funny I've completely lost track go
ahead Cory did you um I'm curious like
if you met anyone in prison that was
like I don't know either inspiring or
someone that scared the [__] out you
like what was the craziest experience
you had in there so there were oh the
craziest experience or the craziest
person whichever whatever you want to
talk about I'm just curious about your
experience I'll give you a sh I'll tell
you about the craziest
experience that was the full scale
riot